Finding Aid for the Norman Lessing Papers PASC.0145
UCLA Library Special Collections
Norman Lessing papers
1943-1982
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lessing, Norman
PASC.0145
8.3 Linear Feet (20 boxes)
Norman Lessing's television career started in 1948. The collection primarily documents Lessing's television writing and includes television scripts, outlines, pilots, and story ideas. Additionally, there are motiom picture screenplays, radio scripts, and stage plays.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Norman Lessing, 1993.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332983606533
Biography
Norman Lessing started his career writing for radio. Eventually he became a writer for television and motion pictures, worked a story editor and producer, and was also a playwright. He began his prolific television writing career in New York City and went on to work on popular programs such as Bonanza, Hawaii Five-0, The Shirley Temple Storybook, Streets of San Francisco, and Your Show of Shows, among many others. His play 36, was performed Off Broadway and in regional theaters in the United States. In addition to his work as a writer, Lessing was also a lifelong chess master. He died in Santa Monica, CA on October 22, 2001.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials related to television writer Norman Lessing. Included are scripts, outlines, and story ideas. Also includes motion picture screenplays, radio scripts, and stage plays.
Organization and Arrangement
The files are arranged alphabetically by project title.
Television writers -- Archives.; Lessing, Norman--Archives.
- Motion Picture Projects
  Scope and Content
  The Motion Picture projects include scripts for Joy in the Morning and The Perils of Paul as well as treatments for Chez Paree and Dance Me a Long Song. The files are arranged by script title.
  - CHEZ PAREE, 6/27/1957 (Box 19)
    General note
    Treatment for M-G-M, 67 pages.
  - DANCE ME A LOVE SONG, 6/17/1957 (Box 19)
    Treatment for M-G-M, 70 pages.
  - JOY IN THE MORNING (1965), 3/25/1964 (Box 17)
    Produced, MGM. Script in FILM SCRIPT COLL. 073.
  - PERILS OF PAUL (THE) (Box 19)
    Original screenplay.
- Radio Projects
  The series consists of script material for radio programs such as Under Arrest, House of Mystery, Hop Harrigan, and The Marriage. Additionally there are a small number of radio sketches. The series is arranged alpabetically by program title.
  - HOP HARRIGAN, 11/25/1943 (Box 18)
    Episode No. 324
  - HOP HARRIGAN, 11/29/1943 (Box 18)
    Episode No. 326
  - HOP HARRIGAN, 11/30/1943 (Box 18)
    Episode No. 327
  - HOP HARRIGAN, 12/1/1943 (Box 18)
    Episode No. 328
  - HOUSE OF MYSTERY, 10/29/1948 (Box 18)
    [Untitled], Program C-145.
  - HOUSE OF MYSTERY, 11/28/1948 (Box 18)
    Ghost On Christopher Rock (THE) (Prod. C-149)
  - MARRIAGE (THE) (Box 18)
    Woman (THE) Chattel. (Jessica Tandy, Hume Cronyn),
  - Radio short short, dramatic sketches (Box 11)
    8 items
  - UNDER ARREST, 2/6/1949 (Box 18)
    [Untitled], Mutual presents:
  - UNDER ARREST (Box 18)
    Missing Goya Murder Case (THE)
  - UNDER ARREST (Box 18)
    Recluse Murders (THE)
- Stage Projects
  The Stage Projects consists of play scripts, including the play 36. The series is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 36, 6/27/1980 (Box 19)
    Prod. by the Jewish Repertory Theatre, NYC.
  - BEACH HOUSE (Box 20)
    A comedy in three act.
  - CITIZEN (Box 19)
    Play in two acts.
  - HE'LL COME BACK (Box 19)
    A play in one act.
  - KID'S CAMP (Box 20)
    Comedy in two act.
  - KRAMER (Box 20)
    A play in one act. (part of Beach House trilogy).
  - LAMEDVOVNIK, 1/27/1982 (Box 20)
    Play in three act.
  - LATE, LATE SHOW (THE) (Box 19)
  - ROCK-A-BYE BABY (Box 20)
    A comedy "dedicated to Superman".
  - UNITED WE FALL (Box 20)
    A drama in three acts. Copyright 1933.
- Television Projects
  The Television Projects represent Lessing's prolific career as a television writer and include scripts from programs such as The Big Story, The Betty Crocker Show, Shirley Temple's Storybook and Hawaii Five-0, among others. The files are arranged by program title.
  - 8 scripts for television shorts (Box 20)
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE), 1/1/1951 (Box 6)
    Episode: Bar Peaceful Murder (THE)
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE) (Box 5)
    Episode: Chinese Mummer Mystery (THE)
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE) (Box 7)
    Episode: Coffee House Murder (THE)
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE) (Box 3)
    Episode: Frame-Up
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE) (Box 7)
    Episode: Long Shot (THE)
  - ADVENTURES OF ELLERY QUEEN (THE), 4/19/1951 (Box 6)
    Episode: Murder For 12 Cents
  - ALCOA HOUR (THE) (Box 13)
    Episode: Great Mouthpiece (THE)
  - ALL STAR REVUE (THE), 6/14/1952 (Box 7)
    Starring Paull Winchell, Jeremy Mahony, Hedy Lamarr.
  - AMMIDENT-DANGER-WINDY, 7/7/1953 (Box 16)
    Adapted for Television by Mel Goldberg.
  - ANN SHERIDAN (Box 15)
    Pilot Script
  - ARMISTEAD BAY (Box 20)
    Series proposal regarding "black-and-white-experience".
  - BARETTA, 8/5/1976 (Box 9)
    Episode: Soldier In The Jungle
  - BATTLE HYMN, 10/26/1953 (Box 16)
    Original television play.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE) (Box 11)
    Episode: Farewell To Love (Written by Ryerson, Florence)
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE) (Box 11)
    Episode: Jason (Written by Raphaelson, Samson)
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 4/5/1952 (Box 11)
    Episode: Night School
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 7/1/1935 (Box 11)
    Episode: Stove Won't Light (THE) (Margaret E. Sangster)
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 2/23/1952 (Box 11)
    No title
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 11/17/1951 (Box 11)
    With Basil Rathbone and Russel Wright
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 12/1/1951 (Box 11)
    With Constance Bennett and Betty Grayson.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 2/2/1952 (Box 11)
    With Jessica Tandy and Hume Cronyn,
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 11/10/1951 (Box 11)
    With June Lockhart and Albert Dekker.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 1/26/1952 (Box 11)
    With Melvyn Douglas and Kay Jamesson.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 12/8/1951 (Box 11)
    With Raymond Massey and Anne Wertsner Wood.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 11/24/1951 (Box 11)
    With Roland Young and Claire McCardell.
  - BETTY CROCKER SHOW (THE), 11/3/1951 (Box 11)
    With Thomas Mitchell and Irene Hayes.
  - BIG STORY (THE), 2/5/1954 (Box 12)
    Show # 268
  - BIG STORY (THE), 9/12/1952 (Box 12)
    Show #203
  - BIG STORY (THE), 10/24/1952 (Box 12)
    Show #209
  - BIG STORY (THE), 12/19/1952 (Box 11)
    Show #217
  - BIG STORY (THE), 1/2/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #219
  - BIG STORY (THE), 1/30/1953 (Box 11)
    Show #223
  - BIG STORY (THE), 3/13/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #229
  - BIG STORY (THE), 3/20/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #230
  - BIG STORY (THE), 4/10/1953 (Box 11)
    Show #233
  - BIG STORY (THE), 4/24/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #235
  - BIG STORY (THE), 5/29/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #240
  - BIG STORY (THE), 6/19/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #243
  - BIG STORY (THE), 9/4/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #245
  - BIG STORY (THE), 11/6/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #255
  - BIG STORY (THE), 12/11/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #260
  - BIG STORY (THE), 1/1/1953 (Box 12)
    Show #263A
  - BIG STORY (THE), 3/12/1954 (Box 12)
    Show #273
  - BIG STORY (THE), 4/9/1954 (Box 12)
    Show #277
  - BIG STORY (THE), 5/21/1954 (Box 12)
    Show #283
  - BIG STORY (THE), 6/4/1954 (Box 11)
    Show #285
  - BIG STORY (THE), 7/2/1954 (Box 12)
    Show #289
  - BIG STORY (THE), 9/17/1954 (Box 12)
    Show #292
  - BILLY ROSE SHOW, 2/27/1951 (Box 1)
    Show #22
  - BONANZA, 11/27/1961 (Box 1)
    Episode: Canary (THE)
  - BONANZA, 6/12/1962 (Box 5)
    Episode: Deserter (THE)
  - BONANZA, 9/13/1961 (Box 10)
    Episode: Frenchman (THE)
  - BONANZA, 9/5/1962 (Box 5)
    Episode: Julia By Moonlight
  - BREAKING POINT (THE), 2/28/1964 (Box 3)
    Episode: I, The Dancer
  - BREAKING POINT (THE), 1/31/1964 (Box 8)
  - BRINGING UP SISTER, 5/1/1951 (Box 15)
    With: Arrival in Brooklyn; Mad Tea Party;and Runaway.
  - BRONK, 6/20/1975 (Box 18)
    Episode: Patsy (THE)
  - BUDDY EBSEN SERIES, 12/22/1972 (Box 18)
    Episode: Rat Defense (THE)
  - BUICK CIRCUS HOUR, 11/4/1952 (Box 18)
    Episode: Election Day
  - CANNON, 8/4/1975 (Box 3)
    Episode: Melted Man (THE)
  - CANNON, 6/23/1975 (Box 1)
    Episode: Wrong Medicine (THE)
  - CARIBE, 12/23/1974 (Box 6)
    Episode: School For Killers
  - CARIBE, 12/31/1974 (Box 2)
  - CASABLANCA NO. 9, 10/28/1955 (Box 5)
    Dimitrios
  - CASE FOR THE PROSECUTION, 1/12/1956 (Box 17)
    First draft - television project.
  - CELANESE THEATER (THE), 1/23/1952 (Box 13)
    Episode: Anna Christie (Adapted from Eugene O'Neill)
  - CELANESE THEATER (THE), 11/28/1951 (Box 13)
    Episode: Counsellor-At-Law (Written by Elmer Rice)
  - CELANESE THEATER (THE), 2/20/1952 (Box 14)
    Episode: Petrified Forest (THE) (Robert E. Sherwood)
  - CHEVY MYSTERY SHOW (THE), 7/3/1960 (Box 7)
    Episode: Murder Me Nicely
  - CHEVY MYSTERY SHOW (THE), 9/25/1960 (Box 4)
    Episode: Perfect Alibi (THE)
  - CHEVY MYSTERY SHOW (THE), 9/18/1960 (Box 3)
    Episode: Suicide Club (THE) (A.A. Milne)
  - CHEVY SUSPENSE SHOW (THE), 6/5/1960 (Box 5)
    Episode: Dark Possession (Written by Vidal, Gore)
  - COURT-MARTIAL, 5/29/1964 (Box 3)
    Episode: Date With Celeste (A)
  - DANNY THOMAS SHOW (THE) (Box 9)
    Make Room For Daddy
  - DIARY (THE) (Box 15)
    Pilot Episode
  - DOOWINKLE, D.A., 11/30/1957 (Box 15)
    Pilot Script: One Man's Meet.
  - EIGHT IS ENOUGH, 1/13/1977 (Box 2)
    Episode: Schussboomer
  - EIGHT IS ENOUGH, 9/23/1976 (Box 3)
    Episode: Unwed Mother (THE)
  - EM + C2, INC. (Box 2)
    Ten Arabs Named Herman
  - ESPIONAGE, 6/5/1963 (Box 9)
    Episode: Good People, Kind People...
  - EXCURSION, 1/1/1953 (Box 5)
    With Burgess Meredith. "Johnny Tremain", parts 1, 2, 3.
  - F.B.I. (THE), 7/17/1973 (Box 2)
    Episode: Break-In
  - F.B.I. (THE), 2/7/1966 (Box 1)
    Episode: Defector (THE) - Part II
  - F.B.I. (THE), 2/7/1966 (Box 1)
  - F.B.I. (THE), 6/1/1972 (Box 2)
    Episode: Engineer (THE)
  - F.B.I. (THE), 10/28/1965 (Box 3)
    Episode: Mellowlane Syndicate Caper (THE)
  - F.B.I. (THE), 1/8/1965 (Box 2)
    Series proposal, 6 pages.
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 12/19/1948 (Box 7)
    Episode: Night Must Fall
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 3/13/1949 (Box 9)
    Episode: Outward Bound (Written by Vane, Sutton)
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 3/10/1948 (Box 8)
    Episode: Room Service
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE (Box 13)
    Episode: Royal Family (THE)
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 6/2/1950 (Box 4)
    Episode: Shining Hour (THE)
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 6/2/1950 (Box 10)
  - FORD TELEVISION THEATRE, 10/7/1949 (Box 9)
    Episode: Twentieth Century by Ben Hecht and Charlie MacArthur.
  - FUGITIVE (THE), 10/20/1965 (Box 3)
    Episode: Not With A Whimper
  - FUGITIVE (THE), 8/6/1965 (Box 5)
    Episode: Wanted: Someone To Drive written by Bill Bast
  - GOLD BAND (THE), 5/7/1954 (Box 18)
    Episode: Soundstage
  - GREAT STORIES FROM LIFE, 9/20/1948 (Box 7)
    Episode: Country Doctor
  - GREATEST SHOW ON EARTH (THE), 1/5/1964 (Box 4)
    Episode: Of Blood, Sawdust, And A Bucket Of Tears
  - GULF PLAYHOUSE, 12/19/1952 (Box 4)
    Episode: Trial Of Charlie Christmas (THE) (Philip Rose)
  - GULF PLAYHOUSE, 10/10/1952 (Box 6)
    Episode: You Could Look It Up by by James Thurber
  - HAPPY JOURNEY (THE) (Box 16)
    For Krafts Playhouse, orig. story by Thornton Wilder.
  - HAWAII FIVE-0, 6/14/1974 (Box 2)
    Episode: Hari-Kari: (Suicide) Murder
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 10/19/1973 (Box 9)
    Episode: Court Martial At Pearl
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 6/14/1974 (Box 2)
    Episode: Hari-Kari: Suicide Murder
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 10/27/1972 (Box 3)
    Episode: Odd Lot Caper (THE) written by Meyer Dolinsky
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 10/2/1972 (Box 8)
    Episode: Percentage
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 11/3/1972 (Box 1)
    Episode: Percentage (2 copies)
  - HAWAII FIVE-O, 3/10/1975 (Box 2)
    Episode: Termination With Extreme Prejudice
  - HIGH IRON (Box 15)
    Pilot episode
  - HIGH TOR, 1/5/1960 (Box 16)
    Adapted for television from Maxwell Anderson.
  - IMOGENE COCA SHOW (THE) (Box 6)
  - JAMIE (Box 18)
    First Day At School
  - JANET DEAN, NURSE (Box 18)
    Richards Case (THE)
  - JEWISH TEHOLOGICAL SEMINARY OF AMERICA, 5/16/1954 (Box 18)
    Sayings Of The Fathers. The Last Rabbi. (2 telecasts)
  - JEWISH THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY OF AMERICA, 4/11/1954 (Box 18)
    Visitor from America (A)
  - KOJAK, 8/20/1974 (Box 18)
    Episode: Dead Is Better
  - LADIES OF THE BIG HOUSE (Box 15)
    Pilot - Return Of The Beak
  - LANIGAN'S RABBI, 11/22/1976 (Box 2)
    Episode: Sitting Duck
  - LITTLEST HOBO (THE), 8/30/1979 (Box 6)
    Episode: Defector (THE)
  - LITTLEST HOBO (THE), 10/31/1979 (Box 5)
    Episode: Great Million Dollar Fur Heist (THE)
  - LITTLEST HOBO (THE), 8/12/1979 (Box 5)
    Episode: Manhunt
  - LITTLEST HOBO (THE), 9/24/1979 (Box 5)
    Episode: Target For Terror
  - LITTLEST HOBO (THE) (Box 5)
    Synopsis of episodes 100-133.
  - LOST IN SPACE, 8/10/1965 (Box 4)
    Episode: O Brave New World (2 copies)
  - LOVE (A) MERICAN STYLE, 12/18/1969 (Box 2)
    Episode: Love And The Partners
  - LOVE (A) MERICAN STYLE, 5/7/1969 (Box 2)
    Episode: Love And The Pill
  - MACGREGOR (THE) (Box 15)
    One-Hour Pilot Episode
  - MAGICAL MONARCH OF MO (Groucho Marx), 12/9/1960 (Box 6)
    A fairy tale for adults with pilot by Gore Vidal.
  - MAX LIEBMAN PRESENTS (Box 18)
    Stanley
  - MILTON BERLE SHOW (Box 14)
    Killer Instinct (THE)
  - MISSION: IMPOSSIBLE, 10/18/1968 (Box 8)
    Episode: Mysticism Of Giles Cary (THE)
  - MODEL MILLIONAIRE (THE) (Box 16)
    Teleplay based on a Oscar Wilde short story.
  - NAKED CITY (Box 6)
    Episode: Contract (THE)
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE, 12/28/1950 (Box 8)
    Episode: Adventures Of Aristide
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE, 2/17/1951 (Box 6)
    Episode: Cut-Glass Bowl (THE) by F.S. Fitzgerald
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE, 3/8/1951 (Box 13)
    Episode: Fiddling Fool
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE (Box 13)
    Episode: Municipal Report (A)
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE, 2/8/1951 (Box 6)
    Episode: Peggy by Rachel Crothers
  - NASH AIRFLYTE THEATRE, 12/14/1950 (Box 13)
    Episode: Windfall (THE)
  - ODD COUPLE (THE), 11/13/1970 (Box 6)
    Episode: Boy Friend (THE)
  - PARADISE BAY, 1/1/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #22 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 1/7/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #23 written by Alison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 2/2/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #24 written by Alison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 3/3/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #25 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 10/18/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #26 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 10/18/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #27 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 10/20/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #28 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 10/30/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #29 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY, 11/1/1965 (Box 8)
    Episode #30 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY (Box 9)
    Episode #96 written by Allison Priestley
  - PARADISE BAY (Box 9)
    Episode #97 written by Allison Priestley
  - PENELOPE'S BOYS, 11/24/1964 (Box 14)
    Pilot Episode: A Kid Named Billy
  - PENNY (Box 16)
    Pilot Script- Mother's Growing-Old Blues
  - PENTAGON, U.S.A., 9/3/1953 (Box 18)
    Chapter Five: The Black Market Baron
  - PETROCELLI (Box 6)
    Episode: Blood Game
  - PETROCELLI, 9/11/1975 (Box 10)
    Episode: Double Exposure (By Katheryn & Michael Michaelian)
  - PLAYHOUSE 90 SERIES, 2/13/1957 (Box 4)
    Episode: Lost Illusion
  - PRESS AGENT (Box 7)
    Life And Times Of Phineas Morwood (THE)
  - PULITZER NEWS STORIES (Box 9)
    Episode: Becker Case (THE)
  - PULITZER PRIZE PLAYHOUSE, 1/2/1951 (Box 13)
    Episode: Hill 346
  - PULITZER PRIZE PLAYHOUSE, 4/9/1952 (Box 13)
    Episode: Jungle (THE) (Adapted from James A. Michener)
  - PULITZER PRIZE PLAYHOUSE, 1/30/1952 (Box 13)
    Episode: Years Of Grace (Adapted from Denis Green)
  - PULITZER PRIZE PLAYHOUSE, 5/21/1951 (Box 17)
    Hostage
  - QUINN MARTIN'S TALES OF THE UNEXPECTED, 2/10/1977 (Box 9)
    Something Out There
  - RAVEN (THE), 5/5/1971 (Box 20)
    Proposal for a half-hour series.
  - ROBON'S HOODS (Box 20)
  - ROUNDERS (THE), 10/13/1966 (Box 3)
    Episode: Greeks Had A Word (THE)
  - ROUNDERS (THE), 5/24/1966 (Box 2)
    Episode: That Sweet Little Old Lady
  - SEARCH AND RESCUE: THE ALPHA TEAM, 7/12/1977 (Box 10)
    Episode: Explosion!
  - SEARCH AND RESCUE: THE ALPHA TEAM, 7/26/1977 (Box 10)
    Episode: Upstream
  - SEARCH AND RESCUE: THE ALPHA TEAM, 7/26/1977 (Box 4)
  - SETTLEMENT HOUSE SERIES (Box 6)
    Street (THE) (for Jackie cooper)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 8/12/1958 (Box 3)
    Episode: Ali Baba And The Forty Thieves (2 copies)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 9/16/1958 (Box 1)
    Episode: Emperor's New Clothes (THE)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 3/5/1958 (Box 1)
    Episode: Legend Of Sleepy Hollow (THE)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 4/29/1958 (Box 3)
    Episode: Magic Fishbone (THE)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 7/31/1959 (Box 7)
    Episode: Magical Monarch Of Mo (THE) ( different drafts)
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 7/14/1958 (Box 3)
    Episode: Rapunzel
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 1/27/1980 (Box 4)
    Episode: Rumpelstiltskin
  - SHIRLEY TEMPLE'S STORYBOOK, 2/21/1958 (Box 10)
    Episode: Sleeping Beauty (THE)
  - SIMON'S WORLD (Box 20)
    Proposal for a television series.
  - STORIES FROM THE BIBLE, 12/26/1978 (Box 10)
    Abraham's Sacrifice
  - STORIES FROM THE BIBLE, 11/1/1978 (Box 10)
    Jacob's Dream
  - STORIES FROM THE BIBLE, 1/23/1979 (Box 10)
    Story of Esther (The)
  - STREETS OF SAN FRANCISCO (THE), 7/1/1976 (Box 1)
    Episode: Drop (THE)
  - STREETS OF SAN FRANCISCO (THE), 9/29/1976 (Box 4)
    Episode: Hang Tough
  - STREETS OF SAN FRANCISCO (THE), 12/5/1976 (Box 1)
  - STUDIO ONE, 3/1/1954 (Box 8)
    Episode: Side Street (Written by Benchley, Nathaniel)
  - SUPERTRAIN, 10/5/1978 (Box 18)
    Episode: Billion Dollar Coffin
  - SWORD AND THE SCALES (THE), 11/2/1974 (Box 7)
    Fire Out Of The Rock: The Case Of Clarence Earl Gideon
  - SWORD AND THE SCALES (THE), 11/2/1974 (Box 7)
    Proposal for series and outline of episodes.
  - TARZAN, 10/7/1966 (Box 6)
    Episode: Track Of The Dinosaur
  - TWO-FIVE (THE), 4/21/1978 (Box 5)
    Competition
  - UNITED STATES STEEL HOUR, 8/18/1955 (Box 14)
    Episode: Ashton Buys A Horse
  - UNITED STATES STEEL HOUR, 3/2/1954 (Box 14)
    Episode: Corner Store (THE)
  - UNITED STATES STEEL HOUR, 9/14/1953 (Box 16)
    Episode: Hope for a Harvest (Sophie Treadwell)
  - UNITED STATES STEEL HOUR, 11/24/1953 (Box 14)
    Episode: Jigsaw
  - UNITED STATES STEEL HOUR, 12/15/1953 (Box 16)
    Episode: Vanishing Point (THE) (A.A. Hotchner)
  - VEGAS, 7/7/1978 (Box 4)
    Episode: Serve, Volley And Kill
  - VENTURE BAY, 10/27/1977 (Box 15)
    Pilot Story - Captain Kidd Is Alive And...
  - WEST POINT STORY, 12/17/1956 (Box 9)
    Big Decision (THE) (aka Attack on Hill 408)
  - WOMEN ARE HERE TO STAY (Box 14)
    Pilot Episode (w/ Polly Bergen).
- Unidentified Projects
  Unidentified Projects series are materials which are not identified with known projects, and which may or may not have been produced. The series is arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - BALLAD OF JACOB STEIN (THE), 9/12/1954 (Box 18)
    Commemorating the American Jewish Tercentenary.
  - BOY WITH A GUN (also known as CROOKED ALLEY) (Box 20)
  - CAPTAIN FROM KOPENICK (THE), 12/23/1955 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. # 9697.
  - CITIZEN (Box 19)
    Proposal for a motion picture or television mini-series
  - ENCHANTED ISLE (Box 16)
    Starring Ezio Pinza
  - EVANGEL (Box 18)
    American history
  - FREEBOOTERS (THE), 5/19/1967 (Box 20)
    Treatment.
  - HARRY IN SEARCH OF HIMSELF (Box 17)
    By John Nesbitt, Passing Parade Films, Prod.9595.
  - JOHNNY BROWN'S BODY (Box 19)
    Original story and treatment.
  - MAN WHO ALWAYS FELL UPHILL (THE) (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9596.
  - MINK AND THE CAD (THE) (Box 19)
    An original story for the wide screen, 58 pages.
  - PASSPORT TO FREEDOM (Hugo Haas Story), 1/16/1957 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9939.
  - PICTURE OF THE MAGI (A), 7/24/1957 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9945.
  - RABBI ON WHEELS, 2/13/1957 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9940.
  - ROSIE (Box 16)
    Chapter I: Rosie Finds a Home.
  - SHE SETTE UP HER LITTLE FOOT, 8/7/1956 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9696.
  - TOURNAMENT, 9/24/1981 (Box 19)
    Screenplay by Lessing, first draft.
  - VICKSBURG - 5:35 P.M., 6/21/1956 (Box 17)
    Passing Parade Films, Inc., Prod. 9711.